## Eric Gibbons

CONTACT Information Magnetic Resonance Systems Research Laboratory

Stanford University 350 Serra Mall

Packard Room 210 Stanford, CA 94305 WWW: www.stanford.edu/~gibbonse

Cell: (801) 916-2620 Fax: (650) 723-8473

E-mail: ekgibbons@stanford.edu E-mail: ekgibbons@gmail.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research interests are in signal and image processing broadly and improving the quality of magnetic resonance imaging specifically. My thesis work concerns improving the quality of pediatric MRI scans for the purpose of cancer screening. This work spans biophysics, RF pulse design, image reconstruction algorithms, and clinical implementation, all with the purpose of advancing human health care.

EDUCATION

# Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA

Ph.D., Bioengineering, June 2017

- Advisor: John Pauly
- Minor: Electrical Engineering
- Thesis: Robust body diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging

M.S., Bioengineering, June 2013

• Concentration: medical imaging and signal processing

# University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA

B.S., Biomedical Engineering, May 2011

- Electrical engineering specialization (signal processing and medical imaging)
- Minor: Mathematics
- Thesis: Correlation-based retrospective concatenation of multi-volume 3D microCT data

Awards

- ISMRM Educational Stipend Award, 2013, 2014, 2015, 2016
- National Science Foundation Graduate Fellowship, 2012
- Stanford University School of Engineering Dean's Doctoral Diversity Fellowship, 2011
- University of Utah College of Engineering Arel Berrier Scholarship, 2010
- University of Utah Barry M. Goldwater Scholar Nominee, 2010
- University of Utah Presidential Scholarship, 2005 2011
- Member of Tau Beta Pi, 2009 Present
- Eagle Scout, 2003

TEACHING EXPERIENCE Stanford University, Department of Electrical Engineering, Stanford, California

#### EE102A: Signals and Systems

Sophomore and junior level course in continuous- and discrete-time signal and system analysis.

Primary Instructor

Summer 2015, Summer 2016

Developed syllabus, created homework, taught lecture, held office hours.

Teaching Assistant, with John Pauly

Winter 2013, Winter 2014, Winter 2016

Held office hours, held recitation sessions, lectured occasionally.

# EE369B: Medical Imaging Systems II

Graduate level course on imaging internal structures within the body from a systems viewpoint.

Teaching Assistant, with Dwight Nishimura

Spring 2016

Held office hours, held recitation sessions, lectured occasionally.

# EE369C: Medical Imaging Reconstruction

Graduate level course on medical imaging reconstruction problems.

Teaching Assistant, with John Pauly Held office hours, mentored class projects.

Fall 2015

University of Utah, Department of Biomedical Engineering, Salt Lake City, Utah

#### **BIOEN 3900**

Sophomore and junior level course in signal processing and analysis with biomedical applications.

Teaching Assistant, with Edward Hsu

Spring 2011

Graded, held office hours, held recitation.

### **BIOEN 5101**

Junior and senior level course in electronics and signal processing with biomedical applications.

Teaching Assistant, with Edward Hsu

Fall 2009, Fall 2010

Developed an entirely new laboratory component for the course, graded, held office hours, held recitation, lectured occasionally.

### Positions

## Utah Center for Advanced Imaging Research, Salt Lake City, Utah USA

Postdoctoral Fellow,

July 2017 to Present

Developed unique MRI reconstruction algorithms using deep learning techniques. Cardiac imaging is the primary application.

# Stanford University, Stanford, California USA

Graduate Research Assistant,

April 2012 to June 2017

Developed a rapid diffusion-weighted MRI sequences for pediatric imaging cases. Pulse sequence development included RF pulse design and reconstruction techniques. This work resulted in a robust protocol that is used routinely at Lucille Packard Children's Hospital at Stanford.

## MedWhat, San Francisco, California USA

Consultant/Technical Advisor,

November 2015 to December 2016

Developed novel machine learning algorithms for the purposes of computer vision and natural language processing. In particular, used convolutional neural network algorithms to identify dermatological conditions and developed a robust question-answer system for questions in the medical domain.

# University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah USA

Edward W. Hsu Research Group

December 2009 to June 2011

Worked to improve dynamic imaging resolution through higher order reconstruction. Developed cross-correlation volumetric stitching algorithm for CT volumes. Ran CT scanner as well performed image analysis on CT volumes.

Center for Neural Interfaces

December 2008 to November 2009

Developed a neural cuff to hold Utah Slant Electrode Array in place while also providing electrical shielding. Conducted over 60 small animal (Fischer rat) surgeries to implant the device. Monitored post surgery walking behavior, explantation, and perfusions to verify biological response to cuff.

University of Utah Nanofab

July 2008 to August 2009

Specialized on environmental scanning electron microscopy. Characterized biological materials through various surface analysis tools.

# Publications

[1] E. K. Gibbons, P. Le Roux, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Slice profile effects on nCPMG SS-FSE," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 2017.

[2] E. K. Gibbons, P. Le Roux, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Body diffusion weighted imaging using non-CPMG fast spin echo," *IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging*, vol. 36, no. 2, pp. 549–559, 2017.

# MANUSCRIPTS IN SUBMISSION

- [1] E. K. Gibbons, P. Le Roux, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Robust self-calibrating nCPMG aquisition: Application to body diffusion-weighted imaging," *IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging*, in review.
- [2] E. K. Gibbons, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Body diffusion-weighted imaging using magnetization prepared single-shot fast spin echo," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, in review.

# Conference Proceedings

- [1] E. K. Gibbons, P. LeRoux, S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Robust nCPMG SS-FSE with accelerated acquisition and reconstruction," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 25th Annual Meeting, Honolulu, Hawaii, p. 3514, 2017.
- [2] E. K. Gibbons, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Slice profile effects on non-CPMG SS-FSE acquisitions," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 24rd Annual Meeting, Singapore, Singapore, p. 1894, 2016.
- [3] E. K. Gibbons, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Body DWI using nCPMG FSE," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 23rd Annual Meeting, Toronto, Canada, p. 2540, 2015.
- [4] E. K. Gibbons, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Single-shot isotropic diffusion weighting with eddy current compensation," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 22nd Annual Meeting, Milan, Italy, p. 2559, 2014.
- [5] E. K. Gibbons, J. M. Pauly, M. Saranathan, B. Rutt, and A. B. Kerr, "A T2-diffusion-prepared cube sequence for brain lesion detection at 7T," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 21st Annual Meeting, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA, p. 2512, 2013.
- [6] E. K. Gibbons, S. J. Holdsworth, M. Aksoy, M. B. Ooi, and R. Bammer, "Analysis of ghosting artifacts for real-time motion correction using EPI," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 20th Annual Meeting, Melbourne, Australia, 2012.
- [7] C. Petty, E. K. Gibbons, R. A. Normann, and G. A. Clark, "Containment for the Utah Slanted Electrode Array," in 5th Annual Mountain West Biomedical Engineering Conference, 2009.

# Relevant Coursework

Medical imaging systems, convolutional neural networks for visual recognition, introduction to digital communication, medical image reconstruction, RF pulse design for MRI, convex optimization, machine learning, linear dyanmical systems, digital signal processing

LANGUAGES

English, native language

Mandarin Chinese, conversational spoken and basic reading/writing skills

Interests

Cycling, skiing, fly fishing, backpacking, analog stereo equipment